[
  {
    "category": "Know Your History",
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "points": 100,
        "question": "Who co-founded Nike and when was the company established?",
        "answer": "Bill Bowerman and Phil Knight in January 1964 under the name Blue Ribbon Sports",
        "answerType": "STRING"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "points": 200,
        "question": "What was the inspiration behind the name 'Nike'?",
        "answer": "Nike is derived from the Greek winged goddess of victory, representing speed, strength, and victory in sports.",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "points": 300,
        "question": "What was Nike's first product, and how did it perform?",
        "answer": "Nike's first product was the 'Nike Cortez' running shoe, which was introduced in 1972.",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "points": 400,
        "question": "What was the significance of the 1996 Olympics for Nike?",
        "answer": "The 1996 Summer Olympics in Atlanta were significant for Nike because they sponsored the U.S. Olympic team.",
        "answerType": "STRING"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "The Main Event",
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": 5,
        "points": 100,
        "question": "What significant endorsement deal helped establish Nike as a major player in the sports industry?",
        "answer": "Nike signed an endorsement deal with basketball star Michael Jordan in 1984, leading to the creation of the Air Jordan brand.",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "points": 200,
        "question": "What was the first Air Jordan sneaker, and when was it released?",
        "answer": "The first Air Jordan sneaker, the Air Jordan 1, was released in 1985.",
        "answerType": "STRING"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "points": 300,
        "question": "How has Nike's sustainability initiatives evolved over the years?",
        "answer": "They introduced the 'Reuse-A-Shoe' program in the early 1990s, which recycles old athletic shoes into material for sports surfaces.",
        "answerType": "STRING"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "points": 400,
        "question": "What was the Air Jordan line, and who was it named after?",
        "answer": "The Air Jordan line is a highly popular and enduring series of basketball sneakers produced by Nike. It was named after and endorsed by the legendary basketball player Michael Jordan.",
        "answerType": "STRING"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Let's Get Musical",
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": 9,
        "points": 100,
        "question": "What is the story behind the iconic Air Force 1 sneaker?",
        "answer": "The Air Force 1, introduced in 1982, was the first basketball shoe to feature Nike Air technology. It was named after the U.S. presidential aircraft, Air Force One.",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "points": 200,
        "question": "When did Nike launch its sustainable initiative, 'Move to Zero'?",
        "answer": "Nike launched its 'Move to Zero' initiative in 2020, which focuses on reducing the environmental impact of its products and achieving zero carbon and waste.",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 11,
        "points": 300,
        "question": "What is the significance of the 'NikeTown' stores?",
        "answer": "NikeTown stores, first opened in 1990",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 12,
        "points": 400,
        "question": "When did Nike enter the soccer (football) market?",
        "answer": "Nike entered the soccer market in 1994",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "People, Places, and Things",
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": 13,
        "points": 100,
        "question": "When did Nike enter the soccer (football) market?",
        "answer": "Nike entered the soccer market in 1994",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
          "Werner"
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 14,
        "points": 200,
        "question": "When did Nike enter the soccer (football) market?",
        "answer": "Nike entered the soccer market in 1994",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
          "Shaquille O'Neal",
          "DJ Shaquille O'Neal",
          "DJ Diesel",
          "Diesel",
          "DJ Shaq"
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 15,
        "points": 300,
        "question": "When did Nike enter the soccer (football) market?",
        "answer": "Nike entered the soccer market in 1994",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      },
      {
        "id": 16,
        "points": 400,
        "question": "When did Nike enter the soccer (football) market?",
        "answer": "Nike entered the soccer market in 1994",
        "answerType": "STRING",
        "alternativeAnswers": [
        ]
      }
    ]
  }
]
